Guide to the Lucretia Tye Jasmine Riot Grrrl Papers MSS.520
Fales Library and Special Collections
Lucretia Tye Jasmine Riot Grrrl Papers
1987-2017
Fales Library and Special Collections
Jasmine, Lucretia Tye
MSS.520
.75 Linear Feet in 1 manuscript box and 1 half manuscript box.
Lucretia Tye Jasmine, also known as Lucretia X, is a Los Angeles based writer, artist, and professor. She is a professor of Art History and Creative Writing at the Art Institute of Pittsburgh, and has created a series of short films related to various ideological of the riot grrrl movement. The collection consists of materials created and collected by Jasmine documenting her artistic career as Lucretia X and her involvement in the riot grrrl movement in the 1990s and 2000s. Materials include original artwork; zines she helped produce, such as Sheila-na-Gig and The Meat Hook; and zines Jasmine collected on punk, indie rock, riot grrrl, feminism, and gender equality-related themes. The collection also includes magazine articles about the subculture, a collection of feminist stickers, and personal essays by Jasmine describing her the experiences in the Los Angeles punk and riot grrrl communities. This collection documents Jasmine's involvement in the movement and the ways in which she actualized her activism through artwork, in addition to illustrating aspects of the riot grrrl scene in Los Angeles and the intersections of feminism, art, and music more broadly.
Scope and Contents
The collection consists of materials created and collected by Lucretia Tye Jasmine documenting her artistic career as Lucretia X and her involvement in the riot grrrl movement in the 1990s and 2000s. Materials include original artwork; zines she helped produce, such as Sheila-na-Gig and The Meat Hook; and other zines Jasmine collected on punk, indie rock, riot grrrl, feminism, and gender equality-related themes. The collection also includes magazine articles about the subculture, a collection of feminist stickers, and personal essays by Jasmine describing her the experiences in the Los Angeles punk and riot grrrl communities. This collection documents Jasmine's involvement in the movement and the ways in which she actualized her activism through artwork, in addition to illustrating aspects of the riot grrrl scene in Los Angeles and the intersections of feminism, art, and music more broadly.
Biographical Note
Lucretia Tye Jasmine (1967- ), also known as Lucretia X, is a Los Angeles based writer, artist, and professor. She received a BFA in Filmmaking from New York University in 1988 before moving to Los Angeles and and becomming involved in the riot grrrl movement in 1992. Her artwork and zine-making motivated her to pursue an MFA in Critical Studies from the California Institute of the Arts in 2006. Lucretia X promotes activism through her artwork and helped produce the zines Shela-na-Gig and The Meat Hook. She is a professor of Art History and Creative Writing at the Art Institute of Pittsburgh, and has created a series of short films related to various ideological of the riot grrrl movement.
Conditions Governing Access
Materials are open without restrictions.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Donated by Lucretia Tye Jasmine in November 2017. The accession number associated with this gift is 2017.234
Arrangement
This collection has not been arranged by an archivist. The materials are arranged in the order in which they were received from the donor.
Zines.; Riot grrrl movement.; Gender, sexuality & culture; Feminism and art.; Feminism -- United States.; Feminism and music; Punk culture.; Fanzines.; Gender identity -- United States
- Some RG Attendees, Undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
- RG Playlist, Undated (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Sticker Ready to Send, Undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
- LTJ RG Writing, 2012-2017 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Function, Undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Housewife Turned ... Assassin, Undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
- dirtboy, Undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Fat!So?, Undated (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Sheila-Na-Gig, Undated (Box 1, Folder 9)
- Revolution Rising, 1994 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- The Meat Hook, 1990-1994 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- Pizzeria Takeout, Undated (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Short Fuse, Undated (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Solidarity Summer Festival, 1997 (Box 1, Folder 14)
- Order a New World, Undated (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Afraid of the Truth, Undated (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Shelf Life, Undated (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Silent Death, Undated (Box 1, Folder 18)
- 18 Road Trips to See Ty Segall, 2015 (Box 1, Folder 19)
- The Abolition of Work, 1993 (Box 1, Folder 20)
- The Realization and Suppression of Religion, Undated (Box 1, Folder 21)
- Anti-Mass Methods of Organisation for Collectives, Undated (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Plagiarism: Art as Commodity and Strategies for its Negation, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Urban Intelligence Listing of Anarchist Resources, 1994-03-03 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- A Lighter Shade of Peroxide, Undated (Box 1, Folder 25)
- The Piece of Shit, Undated (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Sudden Realization, 1997-10-20 (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Fixit, Undated (Box 1, Folder 28)
- 3 Way Street, Undated (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Extinguish, Undated (Box 1, Folder 30)
- Generation Latex, Undated (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Tied & Starved, Undated (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Created by Women, 2001 (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Touche, Undated (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Herbal Abortion, Undated (Box 1, Folder 35)
- We're Not Being Emo It Really Hurts, Undated (Box 1, Folder 36)
- My Zine, Undated (Box 1, Folder 37)
- U.G.L.Y., Undated (Box 2, Folder 1)
- Vivisection Science or Sham, Undated (Box 2, Folder 2)
- CREME BRULEE, Undated (Box 2, Folder 3)
- limousine, Undated (Box 2, Folder 4)
- Ladybird, Undated (Box 2, Folder 5)
- ambivalence, Undated (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Ghost Author, Undated (Box 2, Folder 7)
- The Groupie Gospels, Undated (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Posters, Undated (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Dehydration Fanzine, Undated (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Delusional Felines, Undated (Box 2, Folder 11)
- Riot Grrrl Press, Undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
- "it's a grrrl thing", Undated (Box 2, Folder 13)
- a million pink bedrooms, Undated (Box 2, Folder 14)